<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://2025.djangocon.us">
  <title>DjangoCon US 2025</title>
  <subtitle>Official conference news</subtitle>
  <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/feed" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us" rel="alternate"/>

  <updated
    >2025-09-04T17:58:57Z</updated
  >
  <id>https://2025.djangocon.us</id>
  <author>
    <name>DjangoCon US Team</name>
    <email>hello@djangocon.us</email>
  </author>
    <entry>
      <title>Sign up for Travel Safety Checks & The Latest on Chicago</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/travel-to-chicago/" />
      <updated>2025-09-04T17:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/travel-to-chicago/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to see you in Chicago! We know that travel in the United States may not feel as safe and easy as it has in past years. To help provide some peace of mind, we’ve built a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dcus-automation-prod.fly.dev/travel-safety/&#34;&gt;Travel Safety Check system&lt;/a&gt;. You can enter your contact and arrival info as well as an emergency contact. DEFNA board members will reach out to you via Whatsapp or Signal soon after your scheduled arrival to make sure you made it safely. If we’re unable to reach you, we’ll notify your emergency contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are traveling within the country or flying in from abroad, we know travel can be stressful. If you’re traveling alone, it can feel especially overwhelming, and we want you to know you don’t have to navigate it entirely on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that sounds like something that would give you some peace of mind, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dcus-automation-prod.fly.dev/travel-safety/&#34;&gt;please register today&lt;/a&gt;. Only DEFNA board members have access to the system, and we’ll delete the data 30 days after the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what%E2%80%99s-going-on-in-chicago%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What’s going on in Chicago?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of posturing and public comment over the past week or so about the US federal government sending National Guard troops or Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agents to Chicago. At this point it looks like movements are being made to follow through on this, but we do not know exactly what to expect on the ground–or when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) has increased its activity in the Chicago area. These agents tend to wear masks over their faces, baseball caps, and minimal uniforms that say “police.” If you see people fitting this description, avoid them. They are likely looking for someone particular rather than wanting to investigate the general population in the area. We do not expect them to be active in the downtown area where the conference is located.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The National Guard is making logistical movements that make it look like they are planning to send troops to Chicago in the near future. These are military troops wearing a proper uniform. From what we’ve seen in other cities where they have been deployed, their job is going to be to stand around and not bother anyone. They may well do this in the downtown area near the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Chicago Police Department is completely separate from both these groups and has an official policy of not cooperating with ICE or the National Guard. Chicago Police officers will have patches on their uniforms that say “Chicago Police” and tend to wear a blue shirt with dark pants. They want all our attendees to have a great time in their city and are people you can approach for help should you need it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the United States, you are allowed to record the police and military in public. If you or someone you’re with has an encounter with agents, take a video recording and please report the incident to the Code of Conduct team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not expect any of these developments to directly impact you while you’re in Chicago for DjangoCon US, but we do want to be prepared. Please attend opening remarks each day during the conference as we will provide any updates to these situations at that time. We may also send emails to attendees if there are important developments to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Get Active at DjangoCon US 2025</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/get-active-at-djangocon-us/" />
      <updated>2025-08-29T17:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/get-active-at-djangocon-us/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;🚴🏻🏃🏾🏊🏽🚶🏼 Looking to get active during DjangoCon US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having talks means a lot of time spent not moving while watching talks. It&#39;s important to take care of your body as well as your mind, and a good way to do that is to get moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like a little social motivation (or an excuse to share your accomplishments), we&#39;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/clubs/dcus-2025&#34;&gt;Strava group&lt;/a&gt; as we had in 2021-24. It&#39;s a different group from the last few years, so you&#39;ll have to join again even if you joined in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we send invitations to attendees to join the conference Slack instance (invitations will be sent out to ticket holders by Sunday, September 7), join the &lt;code&gt;#outings&lt;/code&gt; channel if you&#39;d like to join or plan a group exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;at-the-hotel&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;At the hotel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ihg.com/voco/hotels/us/en/chicago/chiwp/hoteldetail/amenities&#34;&gt;voco Downtown&lt;/a&gt; has an indoor pool on the 16th floor. In addition, it has a 24-hour fitness center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the fitness center, you&#39;ll find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise Bike(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free Weights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sauna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treadmill(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoga Mats, Medicine Balls, Weight Bench, Water Station&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the hotels nearby have a fitness center, so make sure you check with your hotel if you&#39;re staying elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;walking%2Frunning%2Fhiking%2Fbiking&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Walking/running/hiking/biking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chicagoparkdistrict.com/lakefront-trail&#34;&gt;Lakefront Trail&lt;/a&gt; is an 18-mile long trail right along Lake Michigan that has excellent paved walking and cycling paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous Chicago Park District Parks nearby. To find some, go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chicagoparkdistrict.com/park-finder/map&#34;&gt;Chicago Park District&lt;/a&gt; and start browsing. As a visual landmark, the hotel itself is adjacent to the fork in the river just above the big C in Chicago when you zoom out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bicycling&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Bicycling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous bike-friendly roads near the hotel in addition to the Lakeshore Trail from above. In addition, if you&#39;d like to go on some longer treks, there are routes to Indiana (&lt;a href=&#34;/assets/gpx/dcus-25-hotel-to-indiana.gpx&#34;&gt;GPX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/assets/gpx/dcus-25-hotel-to-indiana.fit&#34;&gt;FIT&lt;/a&gt;) for those of you who want to check another box off your &amp;quot;states I&#39;ve biked in&amp;quot; list, Northwestern University (&lt;a href=&#34;/assets/gpx/dcus-25-hotel-to-northwestern.gpx&#34;&gt;GPX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/assets/gpx/dcus-25-hotel-to-northwestern.fit&#34;&gt;FIT&lt;/a&gt;) if you want to go see the school&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Stadium_(Northwestern_University)&#34;&gt;temporary football stadium&lt;/a&gt;, or a much shorter trek to Montrose Beach &lt;a href=&#34;/assets/gpx/dcus-25-hotel-to-montrose-beach.gpx&#34;&gt;GPX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/assets/gpx/dcus-25-hotel-to-montrose-beach.fit&#34;&gt;FIT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: these routes have not been tested in person yet. Use them at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sightseeing&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Sightseeing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of landmarks to go visit in Chicago, including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chicago.gov/city/en/depts/dca/supp_info/chicago_s_publicartcloudgateinmillenniumpark.html&#34;&gt;Cloud Gate&lt;/a&gt; (AKA the giant bean) in Millennium Park, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lpzoo.org/&#34;&gt;Lincoln Park Zoo&lt;/a&gt; which is free to enter, and the numerous museums at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chicagoparkdistrict.com/parks-facilities/grant-ulysses-park&#34;&gt;Grant Park&lt;/a&gt;, all of which are within a half hour transit ride or 15-minute bike ride from the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;swimming&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Swimming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chicagoparkdistrict.com/facilities/beaches&#34;&gt;beaches&lt;/a&gt; will be closed to swimming for the season after Labor Day as there will be no lifeguards on duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re probably best off with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ihg.com/voco/hotels/us/en/chicago/chiwp/hoteldetail/amenities&#34;&gt;voco Downtown&lt;/a&gt; indoor pool on the 16th floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hope-you-enjoy-your-time-while-you-are-in-chicago-and-get-a-chance-to-get-out-and-enjoy-the-area!&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;We hope you enjoy your time while you are in Chicago and get a chance to get out and enjoy the area!&lt;/h2&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Be Part of Something Amazing: Volunteer at DjangoCon US 2025 in Chicago!</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/volunteer-at-djcus/" />
      <updated>2025-08-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/volunteer-at-djcus/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to make DjangoCon US 2025 an unforgettable experience while being at the heart of the Django community? We&#39;re looking for passionate volunteers to help make this year&#39;s conference a tremendous success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-details&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; September 8-12, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talks:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday, September 8th - Wednesday, September 10th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprints:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday &amp;amp; Friday, September 11th - 12th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Voco Chicago Downtown. Located steps from the Chicago River and the bustling River North neighborhood, voco Chicago Downtown provides the perfect backdrop for our community gathering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-volunteer%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Volunteer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;give-back-to-the-community&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give Back to the Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volunteering at DjangoCon US is your chance to directly contribute to the Django community that has given you so much. Help create an inclusive, welcoming environment where developers of all skill levels can learn, connect, and grow together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gain-insider-access&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gain Insider Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a volunteer, you&#39;ll get behind-the-scenes access to how a major tech conference operates. You&#39;ll work closely with organizers, speakers, and sponsors, gaining valuable insights into event management and community building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;network-like-never-before&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Like Never Before&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volunteers have unique opportunities to connect with attendees, speakers, and Django core contributors. You&#39;ll naturally meet people throughout the event, building relationships that can last well beyond the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;develop-new-skills&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop New Skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it&#39;s improving your communication skills, learning event logistics, or gaining experience in customer service, volunteering offers practical skill development you can&#39;t get anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;be-part-of-the-magic&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Part of the Magic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s something special about being part of the team that makes DjangoCon happen. You&#39;ll experience the satisfaction of seeing your efforts directly contribute to creating memorable moments for hundreds of Django developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-1&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we&#39;re-looking-for&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What We&#39;re Looking For&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need enthusiastic volunteers who are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Already registered for DjangoCon US 2025 with a valid ticket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passionate about the Django community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliable and committed to their volunteer shifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friendly and welcoming to all attendees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Available for specific time slots during the event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;volunteer-opportunities&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volunteer Opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have various volunteer roles available across different areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration &amp;amp; Check-in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome attendees and help with badge pickup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with registration troubleshooting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct people to sessions and facilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist speakers with microphones and presentation setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor room capacity and help with seating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce Speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Questions to attendees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Talks  Coordination&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can help with the technical stuff that always goes wrong during virtual events. This means jumping in when someone&#39;s audio cuts out, helping speakers figure out screen sharing, or guiding confused attendees through the conference platform. It&#39;s basically being the friendly tech support person everyone needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address questions from the online attendees to the speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-commitment&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Commitment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We understand that as attendees, you want to experience the conference too! Volunteer shifts are designed to be flexible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most shifts are 2-4 hours long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can choose shifts that work around the talks you want to attend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many roles allow you to still listen to presentations while helping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprint volunteers can participate in sprints while supporting the logistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-2&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ready-to-get-involved%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to Get Involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apply-to-volunteer&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply to Volunteer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to join our volunteer team? Have a valid ticket already? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1H4X4X7DtWOKmGe_S0KSZjSuXRjqcps4OUbXzNir2u1U/edit?gid=2088259231#gid=2088259231&#34;&gt;Sign up for slots here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;questions%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about volunteering, don&#39;t hesitate to reach out to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@djangocon.us&#34;&gt;hello@djangocon.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-djangocon-us-2025-unforgettable&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make DjangoCon US 2025 Unforgettable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US is more than just a conference – it&#39;s a celebration of our community, our shared passion for Django, and our commitment to building better web applications together. By volunteering, you&#39;re not just helping run an event; you&#39;re helping strengthen the bonds that make our community special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicago is ready to welcome the Django community with open arms, and we need your help to make this year&#39;s event truly exceptional. Whether you&#39;re a first-time volunteer or a seasoned conference helper, there&#39;s a place for you on our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications are open now – don&#39;t wait! Volunteer spots fill up quickly, and we want to make sure you can be part of this incredible experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, let&#39;s make DjangoCon US 2025 a conference that attendees will remember for years to come. See you in Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Announcing Our Keynotes: Marlene Mhangami</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/keynote-marlene/" />
      <updated>2025-08-04T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/keynote-marlene/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;h3 id=&#34;we&#39;re-honored-to-announce-our-third-keynote-speaker-for-djangocon-us-2025%3A-marlene-mhangami&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;We&#39;re honored to announce our third keynote speaker for DjangoCon US 2025: Marlene Mhangami&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the opportunity to sit down with Marlene and ask her a few questions about her work, her upcoming talk, and what she&#39;s looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-use-django%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you use Django?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly for developing personal websites! It was one of the first frameworks I used in Python so it’s been one of my favorites to use for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-see-django-evolving-over-the-next-few-years%2C-and-what-excites-you-most-about-its-future%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you see Django evolving over the next few years, and what excites you most about its future?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things about Django is the open source community. I’d love to see the community change the way we talk about and use AI, I think in general the AI space needs more creativity, fun and empathy and I think those are things Django can offer. I’m excited to see how people use it in new ways too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-give-us-a-teaser-about-what-your-talk-is-about%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Can you give us a teaser about what your talk is about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk will be about reimagining Django for the age of AI! I’ll be drawing inspiration from the principles that have historically made Django great as a framework and as a community and trying to imagine how that applies today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-you-most-looking-forward-to-at-djangocon-us-2025%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are you most looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends from the community! It’s been a while since I’ve been at DjangoCon US so I’m excited about seeing people I’ve connected with over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-your-favourite-topics-at-conferences%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are your favourite topics at conferences?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love talks that are creative or have a story telling element to them! These tend to be my favorites. I’m also really into AI at the moment so if anyone’s doing something interesting with that, I’ll probably be interested in the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-view-the-connections-made-at-conferences%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you view the connections made at conferences?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are so valuable! I’ve made great friends and even now co-workers at conferences, so I highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-tell-us-about-your-career-journey%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Can you tell us about your career journey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college I initially studied molecular biology on a pre-med track. I thought I was going to be a doctor but didn’t really enjoy the things I was doing. I ended up spending a year in Zimbabwe experimenting with different things and wound up helping girls learn how to code in Python! Ironically, we were using the Django Girls tutorial. I hadn’t been exposed to much coding before that, but after I changed my trajectory and went back to school for software engineering, I ended up getting an internship at Nvidia, and I currently work at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-approach-your-career-growth%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How did you approach your career growth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m genuinely interested in experimenting with code and learning how things work. Sharing my code online has been a big part of my career as well as networking and people in the community. At work I do my best to share what I’m learning, seeing or doing and try to be open to feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-did-you-start-speaking-at-conferences%2C-and-what-has-your-experience-been-like-so-far%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;When did you start speaking at conferences, and what has your experience been like so far?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started speaking at conferences in 2016! I spoke at a few meetups in Zimbabwe and then did my first international conference in 2017 at PyCon Italia! It’s been such a positive experience for me. Speaking has really grown my confidence and I’ve had so many opportunities and friendships come from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-like-to-do-outside-of-your-typical-workday%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What do you like to do outside of your typical workday?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to sleep! Haha, I also enjoy playing tennis, running and reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-advice-would-you-offer-to-attendees-who-wish-to-contribute-to-django-or-its-ecosystem-after-the-conference%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What advice would you offer to attendees who wish to contribute to Django or its ecosystem after the conference?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d tell them they are in the right place!! Documentation is a great place to start when contributing to open source and it should help them learn the codebase more. Even just updating doc strings is a good way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ok-with-people-asking-you-more-later%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Are you ok with people asking you more later?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, always happy to chat and make new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/marlenemhangami/&#34;&gt;Marlene&lt;/a&gt; on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t wait to hear Marlene&#39;s keynote at DjangoCon US 2025! If you haven’t purchased your ticket yet, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;they’re still on sale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to see you in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Announcing Our Keynotes: Zags (Benjamin Zagorsky)</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/keynote-zags/" />
      <updated>2025-07-31T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/keynote-zags/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;h3 id=&#34;we&#39;re-honored-to-announce-our-second-keynote-speaker-for-djangocon-us-2025%3A-zags-(benjamin-zagorsky)&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;We&#39;re honored to announce our second keynote speaker for DjangoCon US 2025: Zags (Benjamin Zagorsky)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the opportunity to sit down with Zags and ask him a few questions about his work, his upcoming talk, and what he&#39;s looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-use-django%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you use Django?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the CTO of Zagaran, a software consulting firm.  We use Django as the backend for a majority of our projects, powering web applications for a whole variety of industries and government agencies.  We&#39;ve used Django to power applicant management for subsidized housing programs, document management systems, Ecommerce ordering and fulfillment, and a medical research platform, to name a few of the many things we&#39;ve built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-see-django-evolving-over-the-next-few-years%2C-and-what-excites-you-most-about-its-future%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you see Django evolving over the next few years, and what excites you most about its future?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m always excited when Django adds new database features because database management is one of the hardest aspects of application development.  Django&#39;s ORM is the area where I believe Django is most ahead of other software frameworks.  The addition of native support for complex database constraints in Django 2, the support for JSONFields across all database backends in Django 3, and the addition of db_default of Django 5 are all features that have made major impacts in the way I plan features on a Django project.  I&#39;m always excited for more things like these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-give-us-a-teaser-about-what-your-talk-is-about%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Can you give us a teaser about what your talk is about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over my career, I&#39;ve seen the power of Django in a lot of different business and technology contexts.  One goal of my talk is to show people ways to use Django that they might never have considered or that they ruled out as infeasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-you-most-looking-forward-to-at-djangocon-us-2025%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are you most looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been going to DjangoCon US for a number of years running, and I&#39;m excited both to catch up with the other conference regulars and make some new friends as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-your-favourite-topics-at-conferences%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are your favourite topics at conferences?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like talks that take a hard look at a particular tool or library (especially a new one), and show both where it&#39;s strong and where it&#39;s lacking.  There are so many tools and libraries out there (far too many for me to try personally), and good talks on these help me tell what circumstances I should try one myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-view-the-connections-made-at-conferences%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you view the connections made at conferences?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that&#39;s so fun about conferences is anyone I meet there could become my next hire, a new customer, a project collaborator, or a lifelong friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-tell-us-about-your-career-journey%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Can you tell us about your career journey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spent most of my professional life running Zagaran, growing it from a 4-person founding team to its current 32 employees.  In that time, I&#39;ve worked on projects for dozens of other companies and government agencies, holding roles that include: individual contributor, product manager, project manager, engineering manager, architect, and CTO (and often more than one on the same project).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-approach-your-career-growth%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How did you approach your career growth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My general philosophy is that when something I&#39;m doing is routine, I should either automate it or teach other people how to do it.  That way, I can spend more of my time working on the problems that no one else at the company knows how to solve.  I also believe that it&#39;s really important to have the diversity of experience that comes from working on many different projects because it lets you distinguish the parts of software that are generic from the ones that are project-specific, and drives more informed technology decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-did-you-start-speaking-at-conferences%2C-and-what-has-your-experience-been-like-so-far%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;When did you start speaking at conferences, and what has your experience been like so far?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been teaching classes internally at Zagaran for about a decade.  In 2016, I started giving talks at the Boston Django Meetup, and have been doing talks at national conferences like DjangoCon US since 2021.  This is my fifth year in a row giving a talk at DjangoCon US, and I&#39;m thrilled to be back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-like-to-do-outside-of-your-typical-workday%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What do you like to do outside of your typical workday?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m an avid board gamer.  I also like spending time with my two kids, and finding ways to combine kids toys to make new toys and games beyond the limits the toy designers intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-advice-would-you-offer-to-attendees-who-wish-to-contribute-to-django-or-its-ecosystem-after-the-conference%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What advice would you offer to attendees who wish to contribute to Django or its ecosystem after the conference?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django needs more support for JavaScript frameworks.  There are a whole range of things that could make this better.  Model serializer functionality and auto-generation of REST APIs should be part of Django; Django REST Framework is a popular third party library that does this, but this is such a common need, it should be moved into the main framework.  There is also a dearth of support for compiling JavaScript in a Django project and mounting compiled JavaScript (especially React components and Vue directives) into Django templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ok-with-people-asking-you-more-later%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Are you ok with people asking you more later?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/zagorsky/&#34;&gt;Zags&lt;/a&gt; on LinkedIn! Also, if you want large-scale help on a piece of software, please reach out to his company at &lt;a href=&#34;https://zagaran.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;Zagaran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t wait to hear Zags&#39;s keynote at DjangoCon US 2025! Stay tuned for more keynote announcements. If you haven’t purchased your ticket yet, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;they’re still on sale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
We hope to see you in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>The DjangoCon US 2025 schedule has been released!</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/announcing-schedule-dcus/" />
      <updated>2025-07-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/announcing-schedule-dcus/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We are beyond thrilled to unveil the 2025 DjangoCon US &lt;a href=&#34;/schedule/&#34;&gt;talk lineup&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;ll have three days of talks on September 8-10, and two days of sprints on September 11-12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have three keynote speakers which will be announced over the next couple of weeks. Stay tuned to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@djangocon&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/news/&#34;&gt;news feed&lt;/a&gt; for the announcements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have lots of great talks lined up, from talks about &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/django-for-ai-deploying-machine-learning-models-with-django/&#34;&gt;Django for AI: Deploying Machine Learning Models with Django&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/from-hype-to-hard-truths-the-rise-and-fall-of-coding-boot-camps/&#34;&gt;From Hype to Hard Truths: The Rise and Fall of Coding Boot Camps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/building-maintainable-django-projects-the-difficult-teenage-years/&#34;&gt;Building maintainable Django projects: the difficult teenage years&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/evolving-django-what-we-learned-by-integrating-mongodb/&#34;&gt;Evolving Django: What We Learned by Integrating MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/the-source-of-change-bettering-online-open-source-communities-can-begin-with-you/&#34;&gt;The Source of Change: Bettering Online Open Source Communities Can Begin with You&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/djangonaut-space-a-mentorship-program-for-open-source/&#34;&gt;Djangonaut Space: A Mentorship Program For Open Source&lt;/a&gt;, and so much more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t forget our awesome deep dive day, where we dig into things like &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/what-a-decade/&#34;&gt;What a Decade!&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/free-threaded-django/&#34;&gt;Free Threaded Django&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;/talks/high-performance-django-at-ten-old-tricks-new-picks/&#34;&gt;High Performance Django at Ten: Old Tricks &amp;amp; New Picks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll also have lightning talks on all three days; you will sign up for those in Chicago. Details will be announced later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t purchased your ticket yet, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;you can get them here!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a reminder, the in person conference runs from September 8-12 in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to see you in Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Announcing Our Keynotes: Carson Gross</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/keynote-carson/" />
      <updated>2025-07-28T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/keynote-carson/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;h3 id=&#34;we&#39;re-honored-to-announce-our-first-keynote-speaker-for-djangocon-us-2025%3A-carson-gross&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;We&#39;re honored to announce our first keynote speaker for DjangoCon US 2025: Carson Gross&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the opportunity to sit down with Carson and ask him a few questions about his work, his upcoming talk, and what he&#39;s looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-use-django%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you use Django?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; very often because my main profession is teaching and we mainly use Java. However, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; community has embraced &lt;a href=&#34;https://htmx.org/&#34;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt;, a web library that I created, and so I have a lot of friends in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-see-django-evolving-over-the-next-few-years%2C-and-what-excites-you-most-about-its-future%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you see Django evolving over the next few years, and what excites you most about its future?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m excited to see how &lt;a href=&#34;https://htmx.org/&#34;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; can continue to drive forward the notion of hypermedia-oriented web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-give-us-a-teaser-about-what-your-talk-is-about%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Can you give us a teaser about what your talk is about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be speaking about the philosophy of Nintendo Game Designer &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpei_Yokoi&#34;&gt;Gunpei Yokoi&lt;/a&gt; who created the original Game Boy.  His philosophy translates as &amp;quot;Lateral Thinking with Withered (or Seasoned) Technology&amp;quot; and I am going to apply that thinking to web development, particularly the combination of &lt;a href=&#34;https://htmx.org/&#34;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-you-most-looking-forward-to-at-djangocon-us-2025%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are you most looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to meeting people and talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypermedia.systems/&#34;&gt;hypermedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-your-favourite-topics-at-conferences%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are your favourite topics at conferences?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy technical deep dives in particular, especially when they start from first (or simple) principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-view-the-connections-made-at-conferences%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How do you view the connections made at conferences?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love making connections, but I am pretty remote living in Montana so they tend to be relatively short lived unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-tell-us-about-your-career-journey%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Can you tell us about your career journey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to college thinking I would be a computer programmer, since I enjoyed it in school.  I dropped out of CS due to being overwhelmed in the program I was in.  I ended up getting a job as a programmer anyway because that was what people were hiring for at the time.  I eventually went back to grad school and finished getting a masters in computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I worked in the Bay Area in a traditional software company for about a decade, then moved on to found a small company.  I eventually had to sell that company due to partner disagreements and decided to move to Montana and try teaching at Montana State.  Over my working career I also created a few open source projects, the most famous of which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://htmx.org/&#34;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-approach-your-career-growth%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How did you approach your career growth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest it has been pretty chaotic, with many moments that seemed hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-did-you-start-speaking-at-conferences%2C-and-what-has-your-experience-been-like-so-far%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;When did you start speaking at conferences, and what has your experience been like so far?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been speaking at conferences since 2016, when I gave a talk on &lt;a href=&#34;https://intercoolerjs.org/&#34;&gt;Intercooler.js&lt;/a&gt;,  the predecessor to &lt;a href=&#34;https://htmx.org/&#34;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt;.  It was to an almost empty room.  It&#39;s gotten better since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-like-to-do-outside-of-your-typical-workday%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What do you like to do outside of your typical workday?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like skiing, fishing &amp;amp; hiking with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-advice-would-you-offer-to-attendees-who-wish-to-contribute-to-django-or-its-ecosystem-after-the-conference%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What advice would you offer to attendees who wish to contribute to Django or its ecosystem after the conference?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I can&#39;t really offer anything specific on this one, other than just trying to do good work &amp;amp; be nice to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ok-with-people-asking-you-more-later%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Are you ok with people asking you more later?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/htmx_org&#34;&gt;Carson on the HTMX handle&lt;/a&gt; on X!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t wait to hear Carson&#39;s keynote at DjangoCon US 2025! Stay tuned for more keynote announcements. If you haven’t purchased your ticket yet, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/%5BDjango%5D(https://www.djangoproject.com/)con-us-2025&#34;&gt;they’re still on sale&lt;/a&gt;. We hope to see you in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Getting to know folks: A pre-conference interview</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/getting-to-know-folks/" />
      <updated>2025-07-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/getting-to-know-folks/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;Hello Djangonauts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US is coming up, and our excitement is building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re spending a little time getting to know people who will be attending DjangoCon US this September. We asked various people who have different connections and experiences with the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/apoorv-garg-/&#34;&gt;Apoorv Garg&lt;/a&gt; is a first-time attendee at DjangoCon US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/richel-agyemang-468379211/&#34;&gt;Richel Agyemang&lt;/a&gt; is a first-time organizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@kati&#34;&gt;Katherine &amp;quot;Kati&amp;quot; Michel&lt;/a&gt; is a long-time attendee, speaker and organizer of DjangoCon US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kudzayi-bamhare-3b6991b7/&#34;&gt;Kudzayi Bamhare&lt;/a&gt; is a first-time speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathan-zeager/&#34;&gt;Nathan Zeager&lt;/a&gt; is a board member of DEFNA and DjangoCon US organizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s get to meeting them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, the remainder of the post switches to first person from the perspective of Velda,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defna.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DEFNA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;director and DjangoCon US 2025 organizer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, thanks for agreeing to this. Let’s start with having you tell us a little about yourself and your connection to the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Apoorv Garg, Technical Lead at InnerGize, previously worked as a Software engineer at Wells Fargo, Talkdoc, Resilient AI and Deloitte. Beyond my professional experience, I am a technical steering committee member for &lt;a href=&#34;https://jderobot.github.io/&#34;&gt;JdeRobot&lt;/a&gt;, an open source organization in Spain, creating an open source toolkit for robotics applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have delivered talks on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pycon.org/&#34;&gt;PyCon US 2025&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.eu/&#34;&gt;DjangoCon Europe 2025&lt;/a&gt; about Carbon footprint from Python Program, observability and monitoring of Django applications using Prometheus and Grafana. I recently joined Django Community as an Individual member at&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/foundation/&#34;&gt; Django Software foundation&lt;/a&gt; and working as a mentor in Django for &lt;a href=&#34;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/&#34;&gt;Google Summer of Code Program 2025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Richel Agyemang, a Ghanaian and a recent graduate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://knustportal.com/knust-bsc-disability-and-rehabilitation-studies/&#34;&gt;Disability and Rehabilitation Studies from KNUST&lt;/a&gt;. I’m passionate about inclusive technology, accessibility, and using design to make a real impact. My journey into tech started from a desire to bridge the gap between disability and digital inclusion, and that led me into UX design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I learned more, I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; while exploring &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; for web development. I was drawn to how clean and powerful it is and was even more impressed by the kindness and support within the community. I didn’t want to just learn from afar, so I joined the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/&#34;&gt;DjangoCon US 2025&lt;/a&gt; team as a volunteer. I currently help with graphic design where I have been creating flyers and graphics for the event and it’s been an amazing experience working with such a thoughtful and inclusive team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Python/Django software engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jpmorganchase.com/&#34;&gt;JPMorganChase&lt;/a&gt;. I became interested in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and open-source code in 2013, and stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/&#34;&gt;DjangoCon US&lt;/a&gt; through its website code hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/djangocon/2025.djangocon.us&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I became a DjangoCon US volunteer in 2016 and served as website chair or co-chair from 2017 to 2020. In 2017, I became a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defna.org/&#34;&gt;Django Events Foundation North America (DEFNA)&lt;/a&gt; Board Member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my eight+ years as a board member, I served as corporate secretary from 2020 to 2022 and took great enjoyment in collaborating on the DjangoCon US website design every year. I frequently attend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; conferences, make connections in person and online, and share what I&#39;ve learned through conference recaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, my name is Kudzayi Bamhare, and I am a passionate coder, teacher, and community leader from Harare, Zimbabwe. My connection to Django began when I attended &lt;a href=&#34;https://na.pycon.org/&#34;&gt;PyCon Namibia&lt;/a&gt; in 2023, where I met some incredible friends who were planning to attend the first &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.africa/&#34;&gt;DjangoCon Africa&lt;/a&gt;at the end of the year in Zanzibar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not wanting to miss out, I dedicated the rest of the year to learning &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; and managed to build some fun projects along the way. Fast forward a few years, and I have now attended all three major &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;)conferences, contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django’s&lt;/a&gt;) documentation, and even helped organise a few DjangoCons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended &lt;a href=&#34;https://momentum.org/&#34;&gt;Momentum Learning’s software development program&lt;/a&gt;, where we used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; for our backend work. Last year I was an organizer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/&#34;&gt;DjangoCon US&lt;/a&gt; and was really impressed with the conference. This year I joined &lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.defna.org/)&#34;&gt;DEFNA&lt;/a&gt; as a board member to continue contributing to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s cool! Can you please share what you are looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently joined as a technical lead at a startup called InnerGize, I am looking forward to meeting leaders in technology on how they have created an impact in this role and learn from them. One thing that I always look for in conferences is to make new connections, learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited about the talks, especially those focused on accessibility and community building. I can’t wait to learn from others, hear their stories, and be inspired by the creative ways people are using Django to make a difference. I’m really looking forward to connecting with people from all kinds of backgrounds who are passionate about open source, design, and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am most looking forward to leveling up my knowledge. I enjoy learning about the latest features implemented by Django fellows and volunteers, and other deep dives. I am also excited that the conference will be held in downtown Chicago this year. It will be an amazing location!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s quite difficult to choose just one thing, but I have to say that I&#39;m really looking forward to reconnecting with everyone from the Django community. I&#39;m excited to hear all the great talks, attend sprints, and visit Chicago as well, but the best part of any conference experience is the people who make it special. You&#39;ll definitely want to stick around for the connections you can make at DjangoCon US!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to meeting back up with everyone from last year and making new friends in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s one tip or trick you would share with someone attending their first tech conference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAC MAN RULE - I learned this rule from a recent conference. If talking in a circle, always leave a space for one more person in that circle, creating more inclusive and welcoming spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be curious, and don’t be afraid to talk to people! Introduce yourself, ask questions, take notes, and be open to learning from everyone you meet because never know&lt;br&gt;
what kind of collaborations or friendships might come out of it. And don’t forget to take breaks when you need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seize the day! Set aside any shyness or doubts. Go up to the author you&#39;ve always admired and chat for a bit. Sit with different people at every meal. Connect with a prospective employer. Learn about a new topic that inspires you. Take time to enjoy some once-in-a-lifetime food and sight-seeing in the host city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m cheating, but I’m going to share two key tips: plan your schedule and pace yourself! Conferences can become overwhelming with so many people, talks, and workshops happening simultaneously; it’s easy to get lost in the hustle and bustle. I recommend reviewing the conference schedule in advance. Identify the events that you absolutely don’t want to miss and carve out time to grab coffee with a friend or introduce yourself to new people at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t feel that there’s one right way to participate in the conference, focus on what feels right for for you (attending talks, meeting new people, coding and asking for help, etc.) There’s no right way to participate and you’ll come away feeling more energized if you listen to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s one word that best describes DjangoCon US (or your feelings leading up to it)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 years / 2 Decades&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empowering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empowerment. DjangoCon US is what you make of it, and the opportunities are endless. My involvement with DjangoCon US has been life changing. It has grown my network, knowledge, and opened doors for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made you decide to attend DjangoCon US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am volunteering this year at DjangoCon US, working in the program committee. So I wanted to gain experience on the volunteering parts, what all things you need to keep in your mind when organizing such big events. And Trust me, It ain&#39;t all easy but at the same time it is fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you hoping to take back to your local community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your expectations going into your first DjangoCon US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am expecting it to be fun and enjoying 2 decades of Django with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you hoping to take back to your local community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apoorv&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoindia.org/home&#34;&gt;Django India Community&lt;/a&gt; to organize DjangoDay India (smaller than a conference, bigger than a meetup). I aim to take my learnings from DjangoCon US to help make me a better organizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- Richel --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What surprised you most about the behind-the-scenes of organising a conference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised by how much teamwork and careful planning goes into every part of the event. From speaker review to website building to grant review to designing&lt;br&gt;
graphics, it’s clear that every small detail matters. Being behind the scenes has shown me how deeply the team cares about making DjangoCon US inclusive, welcoming, and meaningful for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What part of organising DjangoCon US has been the most rewarding so far?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most rewarding part has been seeing my design work go out into the world and be appreciated by the community. It’s amazing to know that I’m contributing to&lt;br&gt;
something bigger; an event that brings people together and creates a positive impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What advice would you give to someone thinking about volunteering or organising?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go for it! You don’t have to have it all figured out. Volunteering helps you learn, meet amazing people, grow your confidence, and discover skills you didn’t know&lt;br&gt;
you had. Just be willing to help and stay open and you will be surprised how much you will gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- Kati --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How has DjangoCon US changed over the years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By design, DjangoCon US has become substantially more diverse. It has been great to see the number of women and Black attendees increase over the years. Everyone is welcome and everyone makes it a better place. Here are a few important milestones. In 2016, the number of women speakers was nearly 50%. In 2017, three women of color keynoted. In 2023, the conference was an important platform for the newly formed &lt;a href=&#34;https://blackpythondevs.com/index.html&#34;&gt;Black Python Devs&lt;/a&gt; organization. By one organizer&#39;s count, we had around 10 Black speakers, and a Django Girls workshop had a majority of Black participants. In 2024, the conference hosted the Black Python Devs Leadership Summit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What keeps you coming back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community keeps me coming back. DjangoCon US is often called &amp;quot;the conference with heart.&amp;quot; I have met so many kind, supportive, inspiring people through the conference. I am forever grateful for the many friendships I have made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s one unforgettable moment or conversation you’ve had at DjangoCon US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kati&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only was DjangoCon US 2017 the first conference that I ever attended, it was my first time ever giving a conference talk! Looking back, I still marvel that I had the courage to get up on that stage and teach a crowd of strangers what I had learned as the conference website chair that year. DjangoCon US loves to be remembered as the place that started speaking careers. Taking that leap of faith was a pivotal moment for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- Kudzayi --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What inspired you to submit a talk to DjangoCon US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had two main reasons for submitting a talk to DjangoCon US this year. Firstly, to fulfil my personal goal of speaking at all three major Django conferences - I’m happy to say I&#39;ll be two out of three by the end of the year! Second, at the end of last year, I set another goal to turn my NBA stat-tracking and comparison web application, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shotgeek.com/&#34;&gt;ShotGeek&lt;/a&gt;, into an open-source project and present it at various Django and Python conferences in 2025. DjangoCon US was at the top of my list, so I’m really proud that my talk was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you most nervous or excited about when it comes to speaking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this might sound a bit unusual, but I’m looking forward to the nervous rush that comes with public speaking; it really makes me feel alive, and I enjoy it haha! I&#39;m also excited and a little nervous about sharing the stage with so many amazing people in the Django community. Their presence motivates me to work hard and prepare an engaging talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What advice would you give to someone considering submitting a talk next year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudzayi&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t overthink it and just go for it! As humans, we often set limitations on ourselves and our capabilities. But I&#39;ve realised that life rewards those who take risks and say &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; to new opportunities. Take it one step at a time. If you&#39;re considering submitting a talk, that&#39;s fantastic! Focus on what you want to discuss, start putting together your proposal, and worry about speaking on stage later. Once your talk is accepted, you’ll have access to a supportive community, including DjangoCon US speaker mentors, who will assist you in preparing for your big day. Remember, everyone is figuring it out as they go, so there’s no point in being the one who gets stuck overthinking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- Nathan --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you keep DjangoCon US aligned with community values?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless opportunities, but one that is important to me is consistently working to make DjangoCon US accessible to more people. One thing that struck me my first year at the conference is how welcoming everyone is to people, like myself, who have limited to no experience with Django. It’s my hope that each year of the conference finds new ways to be accessible, and that the community feels comfortable giving feedback on how we could do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s been the biggest challenge (or lesson) as a repeat organiser?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a repeat organizer I want to bring lessons I learned from last year, but also make space for other organizers to step up and gain experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer Velda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s your proudest moment from a past DjangoCon US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching the hackathon participants present the work they got done in just one week. It was very impressive! I was excited that people wanted to participate and it was fun to be there and support everyone in their accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for spending your time and energy on this, the event, your talks and the Django community as a whole. I’m looking forward to seeing you all in September! For  everyone else, if this has excited you about DjangoCon US, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;buy your ticket today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Introducing Keanya Phelps, DjangoCon US 2025 Conference Chair</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/conference-chair/" />
      <updated>2025-07-21T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/conference-chair/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;This week I had the pleasure of chatting with the DjangoCon US 2025 Conference Chair, Keanya Phelps about her role as Conference Chair and her experience with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-tell-us-a-little-bit-about-yourself-and-your-background%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Please tell us a little bit about yourself and your background?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a mid-life career changer who found my way into tech through a coding bootcamp and it completely changed the trajectory of my life. Before tech, I worked in roles that centered around people, process, and purpose, which now inform how I approach software development, project management, and community building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m passionate about creating spaces where people feel seen and supported, especially those navigating new beginnings, like I once was. Django played a huge role in helping me grow as a developer and find my tech community, so giving back through DjangoCon US feels like coming full circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, I’m a proud wife and mom (both human and canine!), lover of house music, I’m someone who believes in dancing things out and building people up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what%E2%80%99s-your-history-with-djangocon-us%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What’s your history with DjangoCon US?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended DjangoCon US Durham in 2023 and 2024. In 2023, I had the opportunity to speak, which was a huge milestone for me as a newer developer in the community. In 2024, I chaired the sprints, where I got to help create an inclusive, collaborative space for folks to contribute to Django and related projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also submitted the proposal to bring DjangoCon US to Chicago in 2025, a city I love. Stepping into the role of Conference Chair this year feels like a chance to turn inspiration into action to help shape the kind of experience that welcomed and motivated me early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-made-you-want-to-take-on-the-role-of-conference-chair%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What made you want to take on the role of Conference Chair?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who found a sense of belonging and growth through the Django community, taking on the role of Conference Chair for DjangoCon US 2025 felt like a natural next step in giving back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m passionate about creating spaces where people from all backgrounds feel welcome, included, and inspired.  Especially those newer to tech or from underrepresented communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairing DjangoCon US in Chicago is an opportunity to shape an experience that reflects the values of collaboration, learning, and inclusion that have been so important in my own journey. Also, I love building things and this time, it’s not just code, but community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what%E2%80%99s-something-unique-you%E2%80%99re-hoping-to-bring-to-djangocon-us-2025-in-chicago%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What’s something unique you’re hoping to bring to DjangoCon US 2025 in Chicago?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want DjangoCon US 2025 to feel approachable, relevant, and energizing for everyone from seasoned contributors to first-time attendees. We are hoping to intentionally design for inclusion beyond the basics, creating moments of connection, building bridges between technical and non-technical roles, and spotlighting voices that often go unheard. And since we’re in Chicago, I’m excited to infuse the conference with the energy, grit, and creativity that defines this city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-you-most-looking-forward-to-at-djangocon-us-2025%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What are you most looking forward to at DjangoCon US 2025?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m most looking forward to watching people light up when they make a meaningful connection, or feel truly seen in the Django community. There’s nothing like the energy: hallway chats that turn into collaborations, talks that spark new ideas, and the joy of being surrounded by folks who care about both code and community. I’m excited to help create that atmosphere and to witness the magic that happens when people come together with openness, curiosity, and care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what%E2%80%99s-one-of-your-favourite-memories-from-a-past-djangocon-us%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What’s one of your favourite memories from a past DjangoCon US?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite memories is the organizer and speaker dinner at DjangoCon US 2024. It was such a great time, being surrounded by people who care  about the community, sharing stories, and laughter. It reminded me how much heart goes into making DjangoCon what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also loved finally meeting so many of the Djangonauts from DjangoSpace in person. After connecting online, getting to share space with folks I admire and have learned from was so energizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-advice-would-you-give-to-someone-attending-djangocon-us-for-the-first-time%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What advice would you give to someone attending DjangoCon US for the first time?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come as you are! you belong here. Whether you’re just getting started with Django or have been writing code for years, there’s space for you to learn, share, and connect. Don’t be afraid to introduce yourself, ask questions, or attend a talk that’s outside your comfort zone. Some of the best moments happen in the hallways, over coffee, or during the sprints. And remember, everyone was new once, the speakers, organizers, and core contributors.You’re part of this community just by showing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what%E2%80%99s-something-people-might-be-surprised-to-learn-about-you%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What’s something people might be surprised to learn about you?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are often surprised to learn how I made my way to Tech. I made a mid-life pivot after attending a coding bootcamp. Before that, I worked in roles that were all about problem-solving, organizing, and building relationships, skills I now bring into every tech space I’m in.  Also, I’m a huge fan of house music and will absolutely hit the dance floor if the DJ is right. Dancing helps me recharge and stay grounded, it’s my version of debugging life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-parting-words%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Any parting words?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US isn’t just a conference, it’s a community. Whether you’re here to level up your skills, share your story, or simply find your people, I hope you leave feeling more connected, more seen, and more confident in the value you bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep showing up. Keep asking questions. And don’t underestimate the power of community! it changes careers, and sometimes, it changes lives. I’m so glad you’re here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to contact Keanya for questions about being a Chair of conference or any other questions you may have, you can reach out to her via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/keanyaphelps/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-organizers-would-like-to-thank-keanya-for-her-leadership-and-work-with-the-planning-of-djangocon-us-2025&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;We organizers would like to thank Keanya for her leadership and work with the planning of DjangoCon US 2025&lt;/h3&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Announcing our DjangoCon US 2025 Talks!</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/announcing-lineup/" />
      <updated>2025-07-17T18:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/announcing-lineup/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We’re absolutely delighted to unveil the official talk lineup for DjangoCon US 2025! This year’s conference promises to be a vibrant celebration of Django’s community, innovation, and real-world impact. Whether you’re joining us in Chicago or tuning in online, there’s something for everyone—from Django newcomers to seasoned veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;congratulations-to-our-speakers!&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Congratulations to Our Speakers!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A heartfelt congratulations to all the talented speakers whose proposals were selected! Your passion, expertise, and creativity are what make DjangoCon US such a special event. We’re excited to hear your stories, insights, and discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;talks-(monday%2C-september-8th-through-wednesday%2C-september-10th)&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Talks (Monday, September 8th through Wednesday, September 10th)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All talks will be available live for those with online-only tickets. They will be posted to YouTube after the conference for free.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mario Munoz (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mario-a-munoz/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - A(i) Modest Proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eric Matthes (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-matthes-598765205/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Automating Initial Deployments with Django-Simple-Deploy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayush Gauba (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/aayush-gauba-4b1223161/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Beyond Rate Limiting: Building an Active Learning Defense System in Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Mshar (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-mshar/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Beyond the ORM: From Postgres to OpenSearch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Garrett Christensen (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-garrett-christensen/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Big Bad World of Postgres Dev Environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Trythall (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mtrythall/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Building a Wagtail CMS Experience that Editors Love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex Henman (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexhenman/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Building sustainable Django projects: the difficult teenage years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timothy Mccurrach - Cutting Latency in Half: What Actually Worked—and What Didn&#39;t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeffrey A. Clark - Evolving Django: What We Learned by Integrating MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Cheley (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-cheley/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Django as a Database Documentation Tool: The Hidden Power of Model Comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will Vincent (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/william-s-vincent/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Django for AI: Deploying Machine Learning Models with Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paolo Melchiorre (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/paolomelchiorre/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Django&#39;s GeneratedField By Example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Hoolehan - Unleash your Django Frontend: Integrate Web Components into Django Templates with Vue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lilian - Djangonaut Space: A Mentorship Program for Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colleen Dunlap (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/colleen-dunlap-118a5a10b/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Easy, Breezy, Beautiful... Django Unit Tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Riley (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-riley-jr-99366589/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Entering the World of CMS with Wagtail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efe Öge - Peaceful Django Migrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kumar Shivendu - Beyond Filters: Modern Search (and more) with Vectors in Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Micah Lyle (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/micahlyle/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Free Threaded Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan J Sullivan - From Breakpoints to Querysets: Debugging Django With Ease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeanette O&#39;Brien (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeanetteob/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - From Hype to Hard Truths: The Rise and Fall of Coding Boot Camps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Baumgartner (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/pbaumgartner/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - High Performance Django at Ten: Old Tricks and New Picks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karen Tracey (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/karen-tracey-b616255/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - How to Enjoy Debugging In Production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Henrietta Dombrovskaya (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/henrietta-dombrovskaya-367b26/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - PostgreSQL: Tuning Parameters or Tuning Queries?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drishti Jain (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaindrishti/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Python for Planet Earth: Climate Modeling and Sustainability in Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mariatta - Reverse Engineering the QR Code Generator and URL Forwarder Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kattni - (&lt;a href=&#34;https://kattni.com&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;) The Source of Change: Bettering Online Open Source Communities Can Begin with You&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kudzayi Bamhare (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kudzayi-bamhare-3b6991b7/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - The X&#39;s and O&#39;s of Open Source With ShotGeek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timothy Allen (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/flipperpa/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - What a Decade!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lisa Dusseault (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/lisadusseault/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - What Would the Django of Data Pipelines Look Like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rachell Calhoun (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachell-calhoun-0793525a/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) and Tim Schilling (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tim-schilling-5b365a15/&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;) - Why Governance in Open-Source Is Important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Muthig - Winemaking With Mutable Event Sourcing in Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ngazetungue Muheue - Django Without Borders: A 10-Year Journey of Open Source Impact in Namibia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;don&#39;t-miss-out&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Don&#39;t Miss out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to check out these talks and more, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;tickets are still on sale&lt;/a&gt;. We are not having tutorials this year, but we have Sprints on September 11th and 12th. There are no minimum or suggested donations for Sprints, and Sprints are available online as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can’t wait to see you in Chicago (or online)! Congratulations again to all our speakers, and thank you to everyone who submitted a proposal. Let’s make DjangoCon US 2025 unforgettable!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Attention All Hackers! - 5 DjangoCon US Hackathon Essentials</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/djus-hackathon-essentials/" />
      <updated>2025-07-08T10:40:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/djus-hackathon-essentials/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We’re just a few months away from DjangoCon US 2025, and we couldn’t be more excited! This year, like last year, we will be hosting a Django-themed hackathon. It’s a fantastic opportunity to connect with the Django community, unleash your creativity, and showcase your project to the world! Here are five important things to know before the hackathon begins. These details should answer any questions you may have and encourage you to participate if you’re still undecided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1.-sign-up-to-participate.&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;1. Sign Up to Participate.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation in the hackathon is free for all attendees of DjangoCon 2025, whether you have an in-person or an online ticket. If you haven&#39;t purchased your conference ticket yet, you can do so &lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;by clicking HERE&lt;/a&gt;. Once you have secured your ticket, you must register for the hackathon. To register, please fill out this short &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/PupBRVJZdLL9gti8A&#34;&gt;FORM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2.-the-hackathon-schedule.&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;2. The Hackathon Schedule.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hackathon will begin on Monday, September 7th, the first day of the conference, and will conclude on Thursday, September 11th, the first day of sprints. On Thursday, participants will have the opportunity to present their projects to the community. A panel of judges will evaluate each project. Presentations can be done in person, or you can prerecord a video that we will play after the in-person presentations for online participants. If you prefer not to present, you can still participate without presenting; we will share your project afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3.-themes-for-the-hackathon.&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;3. Themes for the Hackathon.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things more interesting, participants are required to build a project that aligns with specific &amp;quot;themes&amp;quot; chosen by the community. The hackathon themes will be announced on the first day via the Slack channel. Don’t forget to enable Slack notifications!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4.-join-the-slack-channel.&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;4. Join The Slack Channel.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All communication and announcements regarding the hackathon will occur exclusively in the DjangoCon US 2025 Hackathon Slack channel. After purchasing your conference ticket, you will receive a link to join the Slack channel before the conference begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5.-work-solo-or-in-teams.&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;5. Work solo or in teams.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are welcome to work individually or as part of a team during the hackathon. There’s no limit to the number of team members, but judges will take team size into account when evaluating projects. Before the conference, you will have the opportunity to connect with other hackers and form teams, if you wish to collaborate, in the hackathon Slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope these tips have provided you with the necessary information to prepare for this year’s hackathon. If you have any questions related to the hackathon, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us through our various communication channels. We are here and eager to assist! DjangoCon US 2025 will take place from September 8 to 12 in Chicago, Illinois. We look forward to seeing you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Contribute to Django at the Contribution Sprints!</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/contribution-sprints/" />
      <updated>2025-07-07T16:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/contribution-sprints/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We are excited to talk to you about contribution sprints at DjangoCon US! They are being held &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, September 11th and Friday, September 12th, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, from &lt;strong&gt;9am to 5pm&lt;/strong&gt; each day at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ihg.com/voco/hotels/us/en/chicago/chiwp/hoteldetail&#34;&gt;voco Chicago Downtown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the same venue as the main conference and virtually on our conference Slack. They are free to attend and open to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📣 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;Get your ticket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and join us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-contribution-sprint%3F&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What is a contribution sprint?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contribution Sprints are a superset of Development Sprints. They serve the same purpose while increasing the range of contribution types and opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with what some people already know: &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.djangocon.us/news/dev-sprint-attendees/&#34;&gt;Development Sprints&lt;/a&gt; are an opportunity for people who maintain open source projects (or want to get involved in doing so) to sit and work together on that goal. They have mostly focused on contributing code, tests, and documentation. However, open source projects often need more than those things. This is especially true as a project grows. Development Sprints are one type of Contribution Sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the new things a project needs as it grows fall under the idea of project governance. Here’s a short list of general governance issues a project may face as it grows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General project governance (Who leads the project? How? How are decisions made? How are new leaders developed? How are conflicts resolved?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding new contributors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Funding/Finance: does your project want it? Is it needed? Who will manage it? How will they manage it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphic/logo design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legal/licensing questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarifying code, documentation, and testing conventions (metadata that guides the rest of your contribution process)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an excellent video on this topic by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b2WHTNE4AZk&#34;&gt;Shauna Gordon-McKeon&lt;/a&gt;, part of the PyCon US 2023 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@MaintainersSummit&#34;&gt;Maintainers Summit&lt;/a&gt;. If you maintain a project, or are interested in helping maintain one, we recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-%26-why-to-lead-a-contribution-sprint&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How &amp;amp; Why To Lead a Contribution Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;why&amp;quot; is clear: if you’ve realized your project needs help especially with things beyond code this is a great opportunity to find that help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;how&amp;quot; can be trickier, so here are some specific suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about the non-code needs your project has.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for help in those areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document the need for that help in your project&#39;s &lt;strong&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/strong&gt; documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it clear in all of your communications that you’re looking for more than just code contributions. Many people still think contributing to an open source project &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; means writing code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📢 &lt;strong&gt;Maintainers&lt;/strong&gt;: Submit your project using &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/XvB5dBiagkrtsAfJ7&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; so we can help others find you during the sprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-%26-why-to-join-a-contribution-sprint&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;How &amp;amp; Why to Join a Contribution Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;why&amp;quot; can vary. Maybe you don’t feel confident enough to contribute code (you probably are, but we understand the feeling). Or maybe you have skills in non-code areas that you would love to use to help a project thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;how&amp;quot; starts with identifying your strengths, then connecting with projects that might need them. Shauna’s video is a great starting point. Once you identify a project that interests you, reach out! Sometimes a project doesn’t realize what kind of help it needs until someone offers it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-to-lead-or-organize-a-sprint&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Preparing to Lead or Organize a Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a project maintainer or contributor, a bit of preparation can help make the most of the sprint and avoid burnout. Most open source maintainers are unpaid volunteers,we appreciate you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some steps you can take ahead of time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your &lt;strong&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/strong&gt; guide is up to date. If your project doesn’t have one, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/encode/django-rest-framework/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Django REST Framework&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pytest-dev/pytest/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.rst&#34;&gt;pytest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/internals/contributing/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://devguide.python.org/&#34;&gt;CPython&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include setup instructions, test commands, code style, CI guidelines, and PR templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rather than just flagging &amp;quot;beginner-friendly&amp;quot; issues, try breaking down large issues into smaller, approachable tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mikemcquaid.com/2019/02/16/stop-mentoring-first-time-contributors/&#34;&gt;Mike McQuaid&lt;/a&gt; of Homebrew has great advice on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;supporting-contributors-as-a-non-maintainer&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Supporting Contributors as a Non-Maintainer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re an active contributor (even without commit access), you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help mentor newcomers with patience and empathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gauge each contributor’s experience level and tailor your help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update documentation as needed to reflect your mentoring experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break down complex issues into bite-sized contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let someone co-pilot an issue with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-hybrid-participation&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Tips for Hybrid Participation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are continuing the hybrid format: virtual and in-person. This brings both challenges and opportunities. While you might miss the spontaneity of in-person collaboration, working synchronously online is a powerful experience. Make sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your project uses real-time chat (Slack, Zulip, Discord, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your docs are easily accessible to virtual attendees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re ready to share screens, links, and tasks in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-notes&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Final Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Contribution Sprints are free and open to everyone. They will run &lt;strong&gt;September 11–12, 2025 from 9am to 5pm CDT&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;voco Chicago Downtown&lt;/strong&gt; and online via Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to lead or organize a sprint? Great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to help? We’d love to have you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have questions? Email us at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sprints@djangocon.us&#34;&gt;sprints@djangocon.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🎟️ &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;Get your ticket now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and be part of something awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Panel Discussion: Two Decades of Django: The Past, Present and Future</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/introducing-discussion-panel/" />
      <updated>2025-07-06T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/introducing-discussion-panel/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce the panel discussion for DjangoCon US 2025:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Two Decades of Django: The Past, Present, and Future&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, a celebration of Django&#39;s 20-year journey and a look at what&#39;s next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderated by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/veldakiara/&#34;&gt;Velda Kiara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, DEFNA Director and long-time open-source community leader, this special anniversary panel brings together key figures from across Django&#39;s technical and community landscape. Together, we will reflect on Django&#39;s evolution, from its early days to its global adoption and look into what&#39;s needed to sustain and grow the Django ecosystem into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation will explore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The moments that defined Django&#39;s past and the ones shaping its future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical challenges and architectural choices ahead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What community health really looks like after 20 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How different roles, from governance to grassroots organizing, work together to keep Django thriving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What we should let go of, and what we can&#39;t afford to lose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our panelists include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tim-schilling-5b365a15/&#34;&gt;Tim Schilling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,Co-Founder Djangonaut Space and Django Steering Council Member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/nessita/&#34;&gt;Natalia Bidart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Django Fellow, maintaining and improving the framework every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachell-calhoun-0793525a/&#34;&gt;Rachell Calhoun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Co-Founder Djangonaut Space and Django Girls organizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/petergrandstaff/&#34;&gt;Peter Grandstaff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, President of Django Events Foundation North America (DEFNA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jefftriplett/&#34;&gt;Jeff Triplett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Django Software Foundation (DSF) Board Member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/loren-crary/&#34;&gt;Loren Crary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Deputy Executive Director at the Python Software Foundation (PSF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conversation is for everyone, from core contributors and community organizers to newcomers curious about Django&#39;s story. Expect honesty and a few laughs, as we unpack two decades of code, care, and community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conference tickets are still available, don&#39;t forget to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;buy your ticket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We can&#39;t wait to see you in Chicago for DjangoCon US 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Childcare During DjangoCon US</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/childcare-during-djangocon/" />
      <updated>2025-07-02T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/childcare-during-djangocon/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;Childcare at DjangoCon US and tech conferences more generally is an important factor that helps folks attend who otherwise may not be able to. We want to make sure that parents feel welcome bringing their children to DjangoCon US and that the availability of childcare is not a barrier to attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assist with that, DjangoCon US will reimburse you for childcare during the conference (up to $150 per day) with a receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nursing parents, we will provide a clean, comfortable, and private lactation space at the conference venue. The room will have a small refrigerator to store pumped milk, labeling supplies, and antibacterial wipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@defna.org&#34;&gt;hello@defna.org&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in utilizing DjangoCon US’s child care reimbursement or lactation space services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also collected information on a few local childcare providers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jovie.com/&#34;&gt;Jovie of Chicago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offers full and part-time nannies and on-demand babysitters. They also provide childcare services for conferences and events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chicagosupersitters.com/&#34;&gt;Chicago Super Sitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provides experienced, trustworthy, and dependable babysitters for different needs and schedules, including one-time requests and events. They thoroughly vet all their sitters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing you -- and your kids -- soon in Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>A First-Timer's Guide to Navigating America</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/guide-to-america/" />
      <updated>2025-06-29T10:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/guide-to-america/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;For many international attendees, DjangoCon US marks their very first visit to the United States. Whether you&#39;re here for the code or the community, this quick guide will help you navigate the essentials of everyday life during your stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;visa-requirements&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Visa Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you can get into the USA though, you may need a visa. Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/visa-information-resources/wizard.html&#34;&gt;US State Department&#39;s Visa Wizard&lt;/a&gt; to determine the type of visa you will need, if any. Our &lt;a href=&#34;/visas/&#34;&gt;Visa Support&lt;/a&gt; page offers more resources, and check out organizer Benedict Kofi Amofah&#39;s excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://iamdreamo.medium.com/a-first-timers-guide-to-attending-tech-conferences-in-the-usa-visa-prep-and-beyond-e2e121db15df&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the visa preparation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a quick guide to navigating life in the United States as a newcomer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;payments-%26-currency&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Payments &amp;amp; Currency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;credit-and-debit-cards&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Credit and Debit Cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit and debit cards are widely accepted throughout the U.S.—including Visa, MasterCard, American Express, and usually Discover. Before you travel, notify your bank to avoid any unexpected fraud alerts that might freeze your account. &lt;em&gt;Tap to Pay&lt;/em&gt;/mobile pay is generally available in the US, but it is not recommended to rely on it soley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;currency-choice&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Currency Choice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When making payments, some card machines will give you the option to pay in USD or your home currency; generally your bank will give you a more favorable exchange rate (even after conversion fees) than the merchant, so you should probably pick USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;carrying-cash&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Carrying Cash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some cases where cards are not accepted, so it&#39;s a good idea to carry a small bit of cash just in case. You will typically get better exchange rates at ATMs over airport currency exchange shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most but not all vending machines will take cards and NFC payments (e.g. Apple Pay and Google Pay), so it&#39;s useful to have a few small bills ($1 is a paper note in the US, unlike most countries) just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobile-phones-%26-data&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Mobile Phones &amp;amp; Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most modern phones that support Voice over LTE (VoLTE) or 5G should work in the U.S. via international roaming. That said, roaming can be expensive—especially for data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re planning a short stay and want to avoid high roaming charges, consider getting a temporary U.S. mobile plan. While the major carriers primarily offer postpaid plans (which typically involve long-term contracts and credit checks), many providers offer flexible prepaid options without contracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boostmobile.com/&#34;&gt;Boost Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cricketwireless.com/&#34;&gt;Cricket Wireless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visible.com/&#34;&gt;Visible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fi.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tracfone.com/&#34;&gt;Tracfone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mintmobile.com/&#34;&gt;Mint Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These providers often support &amp;quot;bring your own device&amp;quot; (BYOD) plans, where you simply insert a new SIM card into your current phone. You can usually order a SIM card online and have it shipped to your U.S. hotel or pickup location. Alternatively, some airport shops in major hubs may sell SIM cards — check the airport directory for availability, especially if you&#39;re connecting through a large hub before arriving in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airalo.com/&#34;&gt;Airalo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.holafly.com/&#34;&gt;Holafly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getnomad.app/&#34;&gt;Nomad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alosim.com/&#34;&gt;aloSIM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpacglobal.com/&#34;&gt;Jetpac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing some internet searches (or asking your friends) might yield some handy discount codes, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sales-tax&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Sales Tax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many countries have some form of value added tax or goods and services tax rolled into the retail price that you pay, so a bottle of water that&#39;s listed as costing $2 is exactly what you  pay. In the US, this is very much &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the case. Instead, each state charges its own sales tax, and in many states, counties and municipalities add their own tax on top of that. Some places charge different tax rates for different classes of goods, such as a discount for food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chicago, Illinois, the combined sales tax rate is 10.25%. This is made up of the 6.25% Illinois state tax, 1.75% Cook County tax, 1.25% Chicago city tax, and a 1.0% Regional Transportation Authority (RTA) tax. So, for example, a $2 bottle of water will cost you $2.21 after tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tipping&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Tipping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tipping (gratuities) culture in the United States is rampant. Here&#39;s a rough idea of how much you&#39;ll be expected to add on top of your goods and services in Chicago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restaurants: 18-20% for everything except for the big-name fast food restaurants (e.g., McDonald&#39;s, Wendy&#39;s, Burger King).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even some self-serve kiosk ordering places will try to ask for a tip! This money will theoretically go to the staff preparing and/or delivering your food, but it definitely feels odd. If service is exceptional, you might consider tipping more than 20%. Some restaurants may automatically add a gratuity for large parties, so always check your bill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee shops: $1-2 per complicated drink order. For a simple cup of coffee or tea, tipping is not strictly expected but appreciated, especially if there&#39;s a tip jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bars: $1-2 per beer/glass of wine, $2-4 per cocktail, or 15-20% of the total tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rideshare and taxis: 15-20% of the fare. While optional on apps, it&#39;s highly encouraged. Drivers often prefer cash tips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hotel room cleaning: $2-5 per night for mid-range hotels, $5-10 per night for luxury hotels. It&#39;s generally recommended to leave it daily, perhaps on your pillow or a designated envelope, to ensure the person who cleaned your room that day receives it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hotel valet parking: $3-5 each time they retrieve your car. If service is exceptional (e.g., very fast retrieval, difficult weather), consider tipping a bit more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transportation%2C-or-getting-from-the-airport-to-the-hotel&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Transportation, or Getting from the Airport to the Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 3 ways to get from the ORD airport to Voco Chicago Downtown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rideshare apps (Lyft and Uber generally have nationwide coverage; which you use is largely up to you) will generally get you where you need to go. It&#39;s about a $40-60 ride (plus tip) from the hotel to the airport in the absence of surge pricing. You&#39;ll pay using your phone. Use the app to find out where to get picked up. The ride should take about 30-50 minutes, depending on traffic, once you&#39;re in the car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traditional taxis may be hailed on the curb outside the airport. Follow signs for Ground Transportation and then look for the taxi stand. Fares will typically be a little more expensive ($50-70 perhaps plus tip), but licensing is stricter. Much like an Uber/Lyft, the trip should take about 30-50 minutes, depending on traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transitchicago.com/blueline/&#34;&gt;CTA Blue Line train&lt;/a&gt; is a cost-effective and direct option. Fares are typically $5.00 from O&#39;Hare to downtown. The trip itself takes approximately 45-60 minutes from the airport to the Clark/Lake station, which is a short walk from Voco Chicago Downtown. You can pay with a Ventra Card (which can be purchased at the airport CTA station) or a contactless credit/debit card. &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; The CTA Blue Line runs 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification%2Fpurchasing-alcohol&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Identification/Purchasing Alcohol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, you must be 21 or older to legally purchase alcohol or enter establishments that primarily serve it (such as bars or pubs). Be prepared to show valid identification, even if you clearly appear to be of legal age. While some places may accept a national ID card, your passport is the most reliable form of ID. Importantly, photocopies or digital scans are not accepted — only the original document will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recycling&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Recycling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recycling is extremely hit or miss in public facilities. Airports typically have some sort of recycling setup, and urban cores typically have recycling for plastic types #1 or #2 and aluminum cans and not much else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other waste goes into a single trash stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-restrooms&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Public Restrooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike many European cities, you&#39;re not likely to find public paid toilets. If you find yourself in need of a trip to the restroom while out in public, you have a few options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public parks often have free restroom facilities (though cleanliness and availability can vary).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retail businesses such as coffee shops, grocery stores, and convenience stores typically have restrooms — but you&#39;re generally expected to make a small purchase first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public libraries are an excellent option; they almost always have clean, free restrooms accessible during business hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flying-home&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Flying Home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your return flight from Chicago O&#39;Hare International Airport (ORD), plan to arrive at the airport at least two hours before your scheduled departure for international flights. Security lines often move quickly, but occasional disruptions can cause unexpected delays. Giving yourself extra time ensures a stress-free departure, especially during peak travel periods.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>It’s my first DjangoCon US. What should I bring?</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/first-time-things-to-bring/" />
      <updated>2025-06-27T15:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/first-time-things-to-bring/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;It’s your first DjangoCon US (or maybe even your first tech conference). Are you concerned about what you should pack? Well we have some thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%93%93-notepad-and-%E2%9C%92%EF%B8%8F-pen%2Fpencil%2C-or-a-%F0%9F%92%BB-laptop-and-charger&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;📓 Notepad and ✒️ Pen/Pencil, or a 💻 Laptop and Charger&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you like your notes a bit more analog? A notepad is exactly what you need. Many people like to leave their laptops in their rooms entirely during talks and take notes on paper instead. Plus, it’s great for logging contact info of people you meet if you don’t have the time or patience to log their contact info into your phone’s contacts immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can&#39;t live without your laptop, make sure you bring your charging cable. There’s ample Wi-Fi at the conference provided by the voco Chicago Downtown, so you’ll have the internet at your disposal. Many attendees will have their laptops open to take notes, follow along with slides, and/or test out the concepts being presented during talks. Plus, it’s much easier to post live updates about talks from your computer than your phone if you’re into that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%92%A7-refillable-water-bottle-and%2For-coffee-cup&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;💧 Refillable Water Bottle and/or Coffee Cup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty annoying getting thirsty in the middle of a conference talk. There will be access to all the water you can drink! Plus, you can be greener by reusing your own vessel instead of single-use disposable cups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are coffee and tea in the conference center as well, so if you&#39;re a coffee/tea drinker, bring your own tumbler if you want extra for the talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%91%95-comfortable-clothes&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;👕 Comfortable Clothes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is welcome, and dress casually and comfortably, whether that&#39;s shorts, pants, a dress, or whatever makes you feel good. It’s up to you to decide what you would like to wear. As long as it isn’t a Code of Conduct violation, it’s pretty much up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the rooms can get a bit chilly, so you might want to have a jacket or sweater handy, but don&#39;t forget the weather outside! September in Chicago is often delightful, with warm days and comfortable evenings. Average daily highs are around 74°F (23°C) and lows around 60°F (16°C). However, temperatures can fluctuate, and a cool breeze off Lake Michigan is always possible, so layers are key!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%93%B1-cell-phone&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;📱 Cell Phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s practically essential for survival in America. The mobile coverage is great in the venue area for all three major providers, so about any device will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%95%B6%EF%B8%8F-sunglasses%2C-sunscreen%2C-and-maybe-a-raincoat&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;🕶️ Sunglasses, Sunscreen, and Maybe a Raincoat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September in Chicago generally brings pleasant weather, but it&#39;s still smart to be prepared. Sunny days are common, so  sunglasses and sunscreen are a good idea, especially if you plan to enjoy outdoor activities. While it&#39;s typically a relatively dry month, rain showers can occur, so a light raincoat or umbrella could be useful just in case. For a more accurate forecast closer to the conference date, check a reliable weather source like &lt;a href=&#34;http://weather.com&#34;&gt;weather.com&lt;/a&gt; or your preferred weather app for Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%8D%BF-snacks&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;🍿 Snacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voco Chicago Downtown will have full breakfast, lunch, and snacks during the breaks (10:10 AM and 3:00 PM) on all conference days (Monday through Wednesday). If you’re an early riser like me, you might want a snack before breakfast (7:30 AM on Monday, 8:00 AM Tuesday and Wednesday). Also, if you have special dietary needs, it can’t hurt to have a spare snack on hand just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;%F0%9F%8E%BD-exercise-clothes&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;🎽 Exercise Clothes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before or after a long day of conference talks, I like to at least get a brief workout in. Chicago offers fantastic opportunities to get out and explore the city! September is an ideal time to enjoy walks or runs along the Chicago Riverwalk, through Millennium Park, or along the scenic Lakefront Trail. You might also find outdoor events or festivals happening in the city during this time. Go for a run, walk, or even a bike ride!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>DjangoCon US 2025: Creating a Safe and Inclusive Community</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/code-of-conduct/" />
      <updated>2025-06-24T06:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/code-of-conduct/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;h1 id=&#34;djangocon-us-2025%3A-creating-a-safe-and-inclusive-community&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;DjangoCon US 2025: Creating a Safe and Inclusive Community&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for another exciting DjangoCon US in Chicago this year, we want to take a moment to highlight one of the most important aspects of our conference: our &lt;strong&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/strong&gt;. At DjangoCon US, we believe that fostering a respectful, inclusive environment is essential to creating a valuable experience for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-commitment-to-you&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Our Commitment to You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;DjangoCon US 2025 Code of Conduct&lt;/strong&gt; serves as the foundation for how we interact with one another, both during the conference and in related online spaces. It&#39;s designed with one goal in mind: ensuring that every participant feels welcome, respected, and safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-expect&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;What We Expect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our community values &lt;strong&gt;professional behavior, courtesy, and respect&lt;/strong&gt; among all attendees. This applies whether you&#39;re attending talks, participating in sprints, networking at social events, or engaging in conference-related online discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, our code prohibits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harassment&lt;/strong&gt; in any form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offensive language or jokes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unwelcome attention or advances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also ask that attendees be mindful about photography and recording - &lt;strong&gt;always obtain permission&lt;/strong&gt; before capturing someone&#39;s image or voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reporting-concerns&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Reporting Concerns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you experience or witness behavior that violates our Code of Conduct, we want to know about it. You can report incidents by emailing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:conduct@djangocon.us&#34;&gt;conduct@djangocon.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with detailed information about what occurred. Our team takes these reports seriously and will respond appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference organizers reserve the right to take action against anyone who violates these standards, which may include expulsion from the conference without a refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-note-on-safety&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;A Note on Safety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everyone&#39;s safety and peace of mind, &lt;strong&gt;weapons are not permitted&lt;/strong&gt; at DjangoCon US events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-on-strong-foundations&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Building on Strong Foundations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Code of Conduct was adapted from the Geek Feminism wiki and PyCon&#39;s Code of Conduct, reflecting best practices developed across the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-us-in-creating-something-special&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Join Us in Creating Something Special&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US isn&#39;t just about technology—it&#39;s about people coming together to learn, share, and grow. By adhering to our Code of Conduct, you&#39;re helping us create an environment where everyone can participate fully and comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re looking forward to welcoming you to Chicago for DjangoCon US 2025, where we&#39;ll celebrate not just Django, but the diverse, respectful community that makes it special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For complete details, please review our full &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/conduct/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; before attending the conference.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>International Travel to DjangoCon US 2025</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/international-travel/" />
      <updated>2025-06-19T15:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/international-travel/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;Are you attending DjangoCon US 2025 in Chicago, Illinois, but you are not from US and need some travel information? Here are some things to consider when planning your trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visa Invitation Letter&lt;/strong&gt;: If you need a visa invitation letter, please use our &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/invitation/&#34;&gt;visa letter form&lt;/a&gt; to request one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visa&lt;/strong&gt;: Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://travel.state.gov/content/visas/en.html&#34;&gt;State Department&#39;s website&lt;/a&gt; for information about US visas. You may be eligible for a visa waiver program (which is an online form—no embassy visit required) or you may need to apply for a visa at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usembassy.gov/&#34;&gt;US consulate&lt;/a&gt; in your country or neighboring country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valid Passport&lt;/strong&gt;: A passport which will expire in a minimum of six months after the date of departure is highly recommended. However, your embassy will have more up-to-date information on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accommodation&lt;/strong&gt;: If you are staying in the conference hotel, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.holidayinn.com/redirect?path=rates&amp;amp;brandCode=HI&amp;amp;localeCode=en&amp;amp;regionCode=1&amp;amp;hotelCode=CHIPL&amp;amp;checkInDate=07&amp;amp;checkInMonthYear=082025&amp;amp;checkOutDate=13&amp;amp;checkOutMonthYear=082025&amp;amp;_PMID=99801505&amp;amp;GPC=DJ5&amp;amp;cn=no&amp;amp;viewfullsite=true&#34;&gt;book your room here&lt;/a&gt;. Our conference rate expires on Aug. 11, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money Conversion&lt;/strong&gt;: Most places in the US will take major credit cards, such as Visa and Mastercard. You can withdraw local currency from your bank account using an ATM if you need cash while you are in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel Paperwork&lt;/strong&gt;: It is a good idea to bring as much evidence as possible to show &lt;strong&gt;the reason&lt;/strong&gt; of your visit to the US, &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; is the conference going to take place, &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; are you going to go back to your home country and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; you do in your home country. Please bring this paperwork with you. These documents can be helpful when going through US Customs and Border Protection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printout of your invitation letter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printout of conference ticket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lodging reservation confirmation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flight reservation, especially the return date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printout of conference schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are a speaker, bring a printout of the invitation email and the schedule section where your talk or tutorial is shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of address: Utility bill to show where you live, copy of lease or mortgage bill, or state and/or federal tax payment bills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of employment or school enrollment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are denied entry at the US border with a valid visa, we will refund 100% of your conference ticket. If you are also an Opportunity Grant recipient, we will also still reimburse travel expenses incurred in getting that far.&lt;br&gt;
Please be sure to review the criteria for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uscis.gov/working-united-states/temporary-visitors-business/b-1-temporary-business-visitor&#34;&gt;B-1 Temporary Visa&lt;/a&gt; if you are eligible.&lt;br&gt;
Make sure to review the criteria for any other type of visa necessary for your home country nationals. There is more information in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://travel.state.gov/content/visas/en.html&#34;&gt;USCIS site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to seeing you in Chicago in September!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Early-bird tickets now on sale!</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/early-bird/" />
      <updated>2025-05-21T06:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/early-bird/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey-django-fans!-%F0%9F%91%8B&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Hey Django fans! 👋&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔥 DjangoCon US 2025 is coming to the WINDY CITY, and tickets are HOT OFF THE PRESS! 🔥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s right, Djangonauts! We&#39;re taking over Chicago this year, and trust me, you do NOT want to miss this Python-powered party! 🐍✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌆🎷🎺 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;GRAB YOUR TICKETS NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 🌆🎷🎺&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we have limited early-bird pricing for individual tickets and corporate tickets. We lowered individual ticket prices to make the conference more accessible and more affordable so that anyone paying to attend DjangoCon US out of their own pocket can more easily do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early-bird individual: $359 (regular price: $499) - SAVE $140!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early-bird corporate: $749 (regular price: $849) - SAVE $100!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⏰ &lt;strong&gt;The early-bird pricing will only be available through the month of May.&lt;/strong&gt; ⏰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting June 1st, tickets will be available at their full price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purchasing your tickets early not only saves you money, but it also helps organizers prepare for the conference. Besides the obvious factors of knowing how many meals to order and what size projector screens we&#39;ll need, it offsets the early payments made to vendors and gives us confidence to enhance and expand the conference experience. If you&#39;re able to commit to attending DjangoCon US early, that&#39;s fantastic. If you need more time, don&#39;t worry; that works for us too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Did we mention Chicago deep dish pizza? Just saying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🍕We can’t wait to see you in Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ti.to/defna/djangocon-us-2025&#34;&gt;Buy your ticket here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>Talk Proposals and Opportunity Grant Applications Now Closed</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/cfps-now-closed/" />
      <updated>2025-05-07T06:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/cfps-now-closed/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;Call for Proposals and Opportunity Grant applications are now closed. Stay tuned via email to hear back about CFP decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opportunity grant notifications will be sent by July 28th, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>How DjangoCon US Selects Talk Proposals</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/proposal-selection/" />
      <updated>2025-05-01T04:55:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/proposal-selection/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;The DjangoCon US schedule is always highly anticipated. But how does it all come together?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey from an open Call for Proposals (CFP) to the final lineup of talks, tutorials, and keynote sessions is a thoughtful and collaborative process designed to foster fairness and showcase the best of the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025-program-timeline&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;2025 Program Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Subject to change depending on the number of submissions and other factors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~&lt;strong&gt;CFP Deadline Extension&lt;/strong&gt;: May 4~&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewer Deadline&lt;/strong&gt;: May 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel Finalization&lt;/strong&gt;: June 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Notifications&lt;/strong&gt;: June 28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule Announcement&lt;/strong&gt;: July 24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start of Keynote Announcements&lt;/strong&gt;: July 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;call-for-proposals-opens&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Call for Proposals Opens&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community proposes talks and tutorials by filling in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretalx.com/djangocon-us-2025/cfp&#34;&gt;CFP&lt;/a&gt;. We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretalx.com/p/about/&#34;&gt;Pretalx&lt;/a&gt;, a platform designed for conferences that support &lt;strong&gt;anonymous review&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;structured scoring&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus, each submission is evaluated based on content, not the speaker&#39;s name or background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anonymization-%26-code-of-conduct-compliance&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Anonymization &amp;amp; Code of Conduct Compliance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the CFP closes, the program team carefully reviews every submission to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymize&lt;/strong&gt; any unique identifying details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensure Code of Conduct compliance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step is crucial for fair and unbiased reviewing. The person responsible for anonymization does not participate in the anonymous review process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-reviews-talks&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Community Reviews Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once proposals are anonymized, we open the review process to a team of volunteer reviewers from the community. They follow guidelines that promote consistency, fairness, and awareness of potential bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reviewer-guidelines-emphasize%3A&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Reviewer Guidelines Emphasize:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focusing on content&lt;/strong&gt;, not style, grammar, or speaker identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaving a comment for all &amp;quot;No&amp;quot; ratings&lt;/strong&gt; (and encouraged for &amp;quot;Maybe&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flagging known proposals&lt;/strong&gt; using a BIAS: prefix and skipping scoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identifying any remaining personal info&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosing conflicts of interest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewers have until &lt;strong&gt;May 18&lt;/strong&gt; to provide feedback on as many proposals as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-deliberation-%26-selection&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Committee Deliberation &amp;amp; Selection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the reviews are in, the committee will lift the anonymization and meet to create the final schedule. At this stage, we look at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review scores and written feedback&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic coverage&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., avoiding repetition like six HTMX talks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker diversity&lt;/strong&gt; (especially elevating underrepresented voices and first-time speakers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company representation&lt;/strong&gt; (ensuring one organization doesn&#39;t dominate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prior speaking history and organizer involvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some talks are accepted or declined based on strong consensus. The most difficult decisions often revolve around the final handful of slots, which we may reserve in case of scheduling conflicts or withdrawals.&lt;br&gt;
The speakers will receive notifications about the decision on or before &lt;strong&gt;June 28&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we evaluate the suggested panellists and hosts who will participate in the last conference day and the discussion topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keynote-speaker-selection&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Keynote Speaker Selection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keynote speakers follow a separate, invitation-based process that begins well before the CFP closes. As outlined by previous DjangoCon US Chair Drew Winstel in &lt;a href=&#34;https://winstel.dev/2024/10/20/what-makes-a-good-dcus-keynote/&#34;&gt;his blog post&lt;/a&gt;, we look for individuals who bring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotional resonance&lt;/strong&gt; and the ability to connect and engage with the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A compelling, unique perspective—reflective&lt;/strong&gt;, funny, challenging, or inspiring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage presence&lt;/strong&gt;, though extensive speaking experience isn&#39;t required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representation of the community&lt;/strong&gt;, especially those who&#39;ve contributed significantly or brought underrepresented viewpoints to the forefront&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keynote announcements typically occur in &lt;strong&gt;July or August&lt;/strong&gt; after the talk schedule is shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US is more than a conference. It&#39;s a reflection of the community that makes Django special. Every part of our program, from anonymous reviews to committee deliberations and keynote invitations, is rooted in care and intentionality. We aim to surface new voices, avoid bias, and curate a meaningful and engaging conference experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>The Call for Proposals for DjangoCon US 2025 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link href="https://2025.djangocon.us/news/call-for-proposals/" />
      <updated>2025-03-04T06:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://2025.djangocon.us/news/call-for-proposals/</id>
      <content xml:lang="en" type="html"
        >&lt;p&gt;We are excited that DjangoCon US 2025 is now open for talk submissions: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretalx.com/djangocon-us-2025/cfp&#34;&gt;call for proposals&lt;/a&gt;! The deadline for submissions is April 27th, 2025 at &lt;a href=&#34;https://time.is/1200PM_27_April_2025_in_Chicago?DjangoCon_US_CFP_Closes&#34;&gt;Noon CDT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you to submit your proposal no matter your background or experience level with Django. Proposals can be from a wide range of topics; non-Django and community topics are welcome. You can look at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://2024.djangocon.us/news/announcing-lineup/&#34;&gt;talk lineup&lt;/a&gt; from last year for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fancy first-timers! If you haven&#39;t spoken at a conference or given a tutorial before, this is your invitation to do so. Don&#39;t let the idea that you&#39;re not famous or an expert stop you from submitting. It certainly won&#39;t stop us from selecting your talk or tutorial and it won&#39;t stop the audience from enjoying it! If you still need help decding on a topic take a look at our own Drew Winstel&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://winstel.dev/2025/02/12/talk-ideas-for-dcus-25/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus there are perks! Presenters get free admission to DjangoCon US! &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/opportunity-grants/&#34;&gt;Grants&lt;/a&gt; to assist with your travel and lodging expenses are available as well. The form for Opportunity &lt;a href=&#34;https://2025.djangocon.us/opportunity-grants/&#34;&gt;Grants&lt;/a&gt; will be released in the very near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on talk and tutorial formats, please check out our &lt;a href=&#34;/speaking/&#34;&gt;speaker information page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want everyone attending DjangoCon US to feel safe, welcome, and included. To that end, we have a &lt;a href=&#34;/conduct/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; for all speakers and attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@djangocon.us&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to see your proposals and can&#39;t wait to see you in Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;
</content
      >
    </entry>
</feed>
